The story of a temporary marriage
Double Harness is a comedy, romance film directed by John Cromwell.
After tricking him into marriage, a woman tries to win
the love of her philandering husband.
Joan Colby Fletcher, played by Ann Harding.
John Fletcher, played by William Powell.
Valerie Colby Moore, played by Lucile Browne.
Colonel Sam Colby, played by Henry Stephenson.
Monica Page, played by Lilian Bond.
Dennis Moore, played by George Meeker.
Double Harness (1933) is an American pre-Code film
starring Ann Harding and William Powell.
It was based on the play of the same name by Edward Poor Montgomery.
A young woman maneuvers a lazy playboy into marrying her.
This was one of several films, all produced by Merian C.
Cooper at RKO, that were out of distribution for more than 50 years as a result of a
legal settlement that gave Cooper complete ownership of the films.
Turner Classic Movies eventually acquired the rights to the films.
The film explores themes of entrapment, businessman,
marriage crisis, bachelor, butler.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.